VUI applications are becoming more and more common place.
VUI 应用程序变得越来越常见
There are a few reasons driving this.
这种情况出现包括以下几个原因
First of all voice is natural for humans.
首先所有语音对人类来说很自然
It's effortless for us to converse by voice compared to reading and typing.
与阅读和打字相比 我们通过语音交流很容易
And secondly, it turns out it's also fast.
第二 事实证明语音也很快
Speaking into a text transcriber is three times faster than typing.
向文本转换器说话是打字速度的三倍
In addition there are times when it is just too
此外 当你散步或开车时
distracting to look at a visual interface like when you're walking or driving.
很容易因为看到视觉界面 受到吸引
With the advent of better and more accessible speech recognition and
随着可以获得更多更好的语音识别和
speech synthesis technologies a number of applications have flourished.
语音合成技术 一些应用程序不断涌现
For example voice interfaces can be found in cars,
例如 汽车上可以找到语音界面
drivers can initiate and answer phone calls given receive
司机可以启动并接听电话
navigation commands and even receive
在观察路况时收到导航指令 甚至收到
texts and e-mail without ever taking their eyes off the road.
文本和电子邮件
Other applications in web and mobile have been around
近几年来 网络和手机上出现了其他应用
for a few years now but are getting better and better.
不过变得越来越好
Dictation applications,
Dictation 应用程序
Leverage speech recognition technologies to make putting thoughts into words a snap.
Leverage 语音识别技术可以很快让想法成为词语
Translation applications, Leverage speech recognition and speech synthesis as well
翻译应用程序 Leverage 语音识别技术 语音合成
as some reasoning logic in between to
以及其中一些推理逻辑
convert speech in one language to speech in another.
把一种语言的语音转换成另一种语言的语音
If you've tried any of these you know it's not quite
如果你尝试过以上内容 你知道它并不完全是
a universal translator but it's pretty
万能的翻译 而是
amazing to be able to communicate through one of
通过其中一个应用程序让你与从未交谈过的人
these apps with someone you couldn't even speak to before.
能够交流 这很神奇
One of the most exciting innovations in VUI today is conversational AI technology.
今天 VUI 最振奋人心的创新是对话式 AI 技术
We can now carry on a conversation with
我们现在利用云系统展开对话
a cloud based system that incorporates well-tuned speech recognition,
这个系统包括已经调优的语音识别
some functionality and speech synthesis into one system or device.
一些函数和向系统或设备中的语音合成
Examples include Apple's Siri,
相关例子包括苹果公司的 Siri
Microsoft's Cortana, Google home and Amazon's Alexa on Eco.
微软 Cortana 谷歌 Home 和亚马逊 Alexa Echo
Conversational AI really captures our imaginations because it seems to be
对话式 AI 实际上可以吸引我们的想象力 因为它看起来像是
an early step toward the more general AI we've seen in science fiction movies.
我们在科幻电影中看到更普遍 AI 的第一步
The Home Assistant devices in this category are quite flexible.
这类中 Home Assistant 设备更加灵活
In addition to running a search or giving you the weather these devices can
除了可以检索 向你提供天气信息 这种设备还可以
interface with other devices on the internet linked with your accounts if you want,
通过你账户连接互联网上的其他设备进行互动
fetching save data, the list goes on.
例如获取保存数据 这样的数据还可以列举很多
Even better, development with these technologies is accessible to all of us.
更好的是 我们所有人都可以获取这些技术的开发
You really only need your computer to get started
你的确只需要让电脑
creating your own application in conversational AI.
在对话式 AI 中创建自己的应用程序
The heavy lifting of speech recognition and
你已经完成了语音识别和
speech synthesis have been done for you and turned into a cloud based APIs.
语音合成的繁重任务 转向学习基于 API 的云
The field is new and just waiting for
这个领域很新颖 等待
smart developers to imagine and implement the next big thing.
聪明的研发人员去想象和实现下一次潮流
There's a lot of opportunity out there to come up with
在这个领域有许多机会 提出一些
any voice and able application you can think of.
你能想到的语音应用程序